<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Entangled: Blogging on Quantum Information, Quantum Algorithms and Quantum Computing</title>
    <link>https://myentangled.com/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Entangled: Blogging on Quantum Information, Quantum Algorithms and Quantum Computing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://myentangled.com/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MyEntangled index: my suggested order of reading</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/08/myentangled-index-my-suggested-order-of-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/08/myentangled-index-my-suggested-order-of-reading/</guid>
      <description>TABLE OF CONTENT
I. About me
II. Study resources: What you should read, watch, and explore at the entrance of quantum computing
III. Stories: My sharing about other events, and some anecdotes and thoughts about what I see, feel and experience in my current walk of life.
IV. Quantum things  0. A no-science introduction to Quantum Information
Introduction to quantum information theory  1.1. Fundamentals of Qubits  1.2 Quantum Measurement  1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randomized Benchmarking (Part 2): Protocols for standard and interleaved versions. Experiments with a realistic quantum device.</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/08/randomized-benchmarking-part-2-protocols-for-standard-and-interleaved-versions.-experiments-with-a-realistic-quantum-device./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 22:52:02 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/08/randomized-benchmarking-part-2-protocols-for-standard-and-interleaved-versions.-experiments-with-a-realistic-quantum-device./</guid>
      <description>Knowing the underpinnings of standard randomized benchmarking addressed in the last part, we first begin with the standard protocol. Standard RB is used to assess the error rate over gates of Clifford group with an assumption that these gates have the same error rate. After that, another improvement of the technique will be introduced, namely Interleaved Randomized Benchmarking. The upgraded version was proposed to not to investigate the Clifford group as a whole, but restricted to one single kind of Clifford gate of our choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randomized Benchmarking (Part 1): A fast, robust, and scalable assessment of Clifford gates</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/randomized-benchmarking-part-1-a-fast-robust-and-scalable-assessment-of-clifford-gates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 22:50:45 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/randomized-benchmarking-part-1-a-fast-robust-and-scalable-assessment-of-clifford-gates/</guid>
      <description>As you can see in the cover figure, quantum computing is just at the onset of its journey. There are tons of work to do before we can move to the next stage of quantum computing, quantum supremacy. Two pivotal constraints to the realization of any useful quantum processor are decoherence and the high error rate of quantum operators, or quantum gates experimentally. It&amp;rsquo;s been suggested that the probability of error per unitary gate should be less than $10^{-2}$ (better $10^{-4}$) for the outcome to be reliable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work and thought about a summer camp for kids from the view of a speaker</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/work-and-thought-about-a-summer-camp-for-kids-from-the-view-of-a-speaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 23:49:31 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/work-and-thought-about-a-summer-camp-for-kids-from-the-view-of-a-speaker/</guid>
      <description>I just have had a trip to Hanoi during two middle weeks of this July. A main purpose that drove me to travel to the same place the second time this year was to give a speech at a summer camp for middle students organized by CKP or Creative Kids Project. I delivered a technology-central workshop, through which I hope to ignite my students&amp;rsquo; curiosty towards technology and programming particularly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error rate vs Fidelity (Part 1): Unveil the mathematics behind quantum error rate</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/error-rate-vs-fidelity-part-1-unveil-the-mathematics-behind-quantum-error-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 16:39:35 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/error-rate-vs-fidelity-part-1-unveil-the-mathematics-behind-quantum-error-rate/</guid>
      <description>In the article of Bernsterin-Vazirani implementation, I&amp;rsquo;ve addressed one of the most crucial challenges of quantum computing. The field is yet to flourish because quantum gates aren&amp;rsquo;t constructed to be good enough. One major difference of quantum gates versus classical counterparts is that quantum gates have to be reversible, which means we&amp;rsquo;re able to retrieve a prior state of a qubit without loss of information. Scientists are now on their way to establish a proper scheme for building decent quantum gates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed States and General Quantum Operations: A simple view on the framework of Quantum Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/mixed-states-and-general-quantum-operations-a-simple-view-on-the-framework-of-quantum-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 23:45:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/mixed-states-and-general-quantum-operations-a-simple-view-on-the-framework-of-quantum-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>In this text I&amp;rsquo;ll do some review on the definition of quantum state and quantum measurement, which was introduced here, and reasonably expand the notions into the most general instances of quantum bits.
Review Given a state $$|\psi\rangle = \sum_i \alpha_i |\varphi_i \rangle,$$ it&amp;rsquo;s possible to perform a Von Neumann measurement on the state&amp;rsquo;s space $\mathscr{H}$ with respect to the orthonormal basis $B = \{|\varphi_i \rangle\}$. The output would be a label $i$ with corresponding probability $|\alpha_i|^2$ and the system left in state $|\varphi_i\rangle$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernstein-Vazirani algorithm (Part 2): How to run your algorithms on a realistic quantum computer</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/06/bernstein-vazirani-algorithm-part-2-how-to-run-your-algorithms-on-a-realistic-quantum-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 15:30:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/06/bernstein-vazirani-algorithm-part-2-how-to-run-your-algorithms-on-a-realistic-quantum-computer/</guid>
      <description>In the last part of the previous series, Deutsch algorithm, I introduced a manual way to construct the oracle. That oracle must be built from matrix because the oracle function is undeterminate except for the outcome. In Bernsterin-Vazirani problem, the function is, on the other hand, clearly stated: $f(\mathbf{x}) = \mathbf{s}\cdot\mathbf{x}$. So, it&amp;rsquo;s unnecessary to repeat the previous procedure; instead, we&amp;rsquo;ll build the oracle without using matrices by understanding what the function really do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernstein-Vazirani algorithm (Part 1): A derivation of the Deutsch-Jozsa algorithm</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/bernstein-vazirani-algorithm-part-1-a-derivation-of-the-deutsch-jozsa-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 18:10:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/bernstein-vazirani-algorithm-part-1-a-derivation-of-the-deutsch-jozsa-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Here we stop by Berstein-Vazirani problem that inherents the structure of its predecessor, Deutsch-Jozsa problem, before we can get started with problems and solutions of practical meaning later. Because this problem is similar to the one stated in the last series, we&amp;rsquo;ll get straight to it.
Berstein-Vazirani problem The access for a black-box function $f: \{0,1\}^n \mapsto \{0,1\}$. It&amp;rsquo;s guaranteed that $f(\mathbf{x}) = \mathbf{s}\cdot\mathbf{x}$ (mod $2$) for some secret string $\mathbf{s} \in \{0,1\}^n$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[TUYỂN SINH] PiMA 2019 - The Mathematics of Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/tuy%E1%BB%83n-sinh-pima-2019-the-mathematics-of-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 14:12:08 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/tuy%E1%BB%83n-sinh-pima-2019-the-mathematics-of-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Nối tiếp ba mùa trại 2016, 2017 và 2018 đầy thành công, PiMA chính thức quay trở lại với chủ đề “The Mathematics of Deep Learning”.
I. Đôi nét về PiMA Chúng mình là ai? Projects in Mathematics and Applications (PiMA) là một dự án phi lợi nhuận được thành lập năm 2016 bởi một nhóm sinh viên có niềm đam mê với Toán ứng dụng từ các trường đại học ở nhiều nơi trên thế giới.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deutsch Algorithm (Part 3): Implementation of oracle-based algorithms</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-3-implementation-of-oracle-based-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 22:50:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-3-implementation-of-oracle-based-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Because the Deutsch algorithm is just a simple instance of the Deutsch-Jozsa algorithm where $n=2$, we&amp;rsquo;ll only discuss how to implement the general one. Let&amp;rsquo;s go.
Difficulty of reconstructing gates from matrices This is the first time we encounter a so-called black-box function in an algorithm. It&amp;rsquo;s called a black box since we don&amp;rsquo;t how it calculate the output from the input, but we do know the output it returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deutsch Algorithm (Part 2): Deutsch-Jozsa problem - The first exponential speedup</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-2-deutsch-jozsa-problem-the-first-exponential-speedup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:53:35 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-2-deutsch-jozsa-problem-the-first-exponential-speedup/</guid>
      <description>Here we&amp;rsquo;re gonna see the most impressive quantum algorithm in terms of query complexity. The algorithm is an generalization of the original Deutsch algorithm we discussed in the last post. But I want to say that this algorithm may not be as extraordinary as you may think of it. It was created to solve a kind of problem that has zero practical meaning for the purpose of demonstrating how strong quantum computing can reach compared to classical computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deutsch Algorithm (Part 1): Kicking the phase back</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-1-kicking-the-phase-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:57:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-1-kicking-the-phase-back/</guid>
      <description>I have said something like quantum computing can overpower classical computing several times before. In this series, I&amp;rsquo;m going to showing you a problem with a quantum algorithm that is exponentially faster in terms of complexity than any classical solution. In this text, we&amp;rsquo;re going to explore an essential technique and apply it to solve the simplest version of Deutsch problem.
 Phase kick-back One concept you may encouter numerous times in a Linear Algebra class is eigenvalues and eigenvectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Resources</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/study-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 23:54:17 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/study-resources/</guid>
      <description>Unlike several rising branches of computer science such as artificial intellgence and machine learning, quantum computing is still young when it comes to the development level. Most widely used quantum programming languages and libraries are created for people to learn and experiment with their ideas rather than for publishing any kind of commercial product. Generally speaking, the field has a weak application side; its focus strongly lies in interpreting quantum information theories and&amp;hellip; build some funny stuffs for the sake of learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I and what the fish is this blog?</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/who-am-i-and-what-the-fish-is-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 22:27:24 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/who-am-i-and-what-the-fish-is-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>About me Hi, my name is Entangled, a cat who adopted a boy named Trong, my hooman slave&amp;hellip; I liken&amp;rsquo;t when he laughed watching videos of other cats showing off their cuteness. He&amp;rsquo;s textroverted that is apparently energetic in a texting conversation but may dumb as a fish in a face-to-face. Just send him cat footages to get him engaged.
Okay, here&amp;rsquo;s the truth. He&amp;rsquo;s a coming student at KAIST (Korean Advanced Institute of Science and Technology) and inclined to major in Physics plus Computer Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Teleportation (Part 2): The Art of transporting the Unknown</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-2-the-art-of-transporting-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 15:26:47 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-2-the-art-of-transporting-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Suppose Trong has just created a wonderful qubit in his lab. He knows his qubit look like $|\psi\rangle = \alpha |0\rangle + \beta |1\rangle$ but doesn&amp;rsquo;t know $\alpha$ and $\beta$. Now he wants to transport this qubit to his crush, but they don&amp;rsquo;t have a quantum channel that can help transport quantum information. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s a very bad idea for Trong to try to figure out $\alpha$ and $\beta$ through measurement because if he does so, he&amp;rsquo;ll destroy his qubit but only learn extremely little information about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Teleportation (Part 3): Implementation</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-3-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 15:26:47 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-3-implementation/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s implement and verify the teleporation protocol following the procedure we discussed throughout previous parts.
First we need to create an arbitrary quantum state. Trong has been curious about the combined effect of rotation gates about the x, y, and z axes. So, he decides to apply three distinct rotation gates, each as a rotation of 60 degrees around one coordinate axis acting on a qubit currently in the Hadamard state $|-\rangle$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Teleportation (Part 1): Preliminaries</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-1-preliminaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 15:26:46 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-1-preliminaries/</guid>
      <description>Here we start exploring a core of Quantum Computing: Quantum Algorithms. Before we dive into the dark and deep pool of such algorithms, it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to get familiar with a fundamental constraint to Quantum Computing. In contrast, I&amp;rsquo;ll also introduce you how powerful qubits get in solving problems through a basic protocol: Quantum Teleportation, the &amp;ldquo;Hello, world!&amp;rdquo; of Quantum Programming.
 No-cloning theorem In terms of computer architechture, it&amp;rsquo;s convenient to copy the state of a bit in order to create a new qubit exactly the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A formal approach to Observables and Measurements</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/a-formal-approach-to-observables-and-measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 11:09:30 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/a-formal-approach-to-observables-and-measurements/</guid>
      <description>Throughout previous posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve delivered a way to understand what is a quantum measurement. That way of understanding is simple and may suit our normal intuition, but measurement is a non-trivial physical process and somewhat counter-intuitive for several reasons.
First, a measurement in general results in probabilistic outcomes. No matter how careful you prepare for the measurement procedure, it is inherent that possible outcomes of a measure is distributed according to a certain probability distribution determined by the state space of your quantum system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Operations: Unitary and Reversible Matrices</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-operations-unitary-and-reversible-matrices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 10:58:21 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-operations-unitary-and-reversible-matrices/</guid>
      <description>Source of image: Quantum Computer Explained - Limits of Human Technology  (Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell) 
In classical computation, there are four basic operations that act on information bits, namely Identity (no operation), Negation (NOT), Conjunction (AND), and Disjunction (OR). All other operations are secondary and built upon these four operations. That being said, with the primary and secondary operations, one is able to perform any calculation in classical fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Entanglement to cheat the Reality</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-entanglement-to-cheat-the-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 23:59:42 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-entanglement-to-cheat-the-reality/</guid>
      <description>Quantum entanglement Have you ever thought of a situation when the happening of an event in an isolated environment dictates the result of another event also in an isolated environment with no communication allowed? That sounds infeasible in our view of reality, except that these two separated events share a somewhat telepathic power. Yes, this telepathy really happens in the realm of quantum entanglement. The phenomenon can be simplified that the result of the first measurement reveals information about the result of the second measurement despite an absolute separation and no communication setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Measurement: Not just 0 and 1</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-measurement-not-just-0-and-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 10:58:21 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-measurement-not-just-0-and-1/</guid>
      <description>Quantum entanglement is, by definition, a phenomenon that the combined state of a set of qubits cannot be described as a product of the states of each qubit of that set, which also means the entangled state contains hidden information that one cannot reveal through examining separate qubits. In this text, I&amp;rsquo;m going to introduce and discuss several aspects of this spectacular phenomenon.
Measurement in different bases In previous posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned that a qubit can be in a superposition of its basis states $\left|0\right\rangle$ and $\left|1\right\rangle$ with corresponding complex amplitudes $a_0$ and $a_1$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qubits: The substitution of bits in quantum scenario</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/qubits-the-substitution-of-bits-in-quantum-scenario/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 16:39:36 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/qubits-the-substitution-of-bits-in-quantum-scenario/</guid>
      <description>Source of image: Quantum Computer Explained - Limits of Human Technology  (Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell) 
As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned in my previous post, qubits doesn&amp;rsquo;t suffer from the limitation of only being $0$ or $1$. Within this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about some background knowledge essential for ones who have just stepped into the field like me.
Single Qubit Dirac notation $\left | \cdot \right\rangle$ (pronounced as ket) is adopted to indicate qubit states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A half-alive-half-dead cat and the beginning of Quantum Information</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/a-half-alive-half-dead-cat-and-the-beginning-of-quantum-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 19:47:20 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/a-half-alive-half-dead-cat-and-the-beginning-of-quantum-information/</guid>
      <description>You may have heard of quantum information promising many prospects in revolutionizing the future of computers? When I was a high-schooler years ago, I also got amazed by these statements repeated in pop science articles. But to what extent this statement is true? Before we come to a final conclusion, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look on historical milestones of the field.
The duration from the 1900s to 1930s was the golden age of quantum mechanics with many groundbreaking findings that established a concrete theoretical foundation for quantum information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>