<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantum Algorithms on </title>
    <link>https://myentangled.com/en/categories/quantum-algorithms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quantum Algorithms on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 22:50:19 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://myentangled.com/en/categories/quantum-algorithms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deutsch Algorithm (Part 3): Implementation of oracle-based algorithms</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-3-implementation-of-oracle-based-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 22:50:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-3-implementation-of-oracle-based-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Because the Deutsch algorithm is just a simple instance of the Deutsch-Jozsa algorithm where $n=2$, we&amp;rsquo;ll only discuss how to implement the general one. Let&amp;rsquo;s go.
Difficulty of reconstructing gates from matrices This is the first time we encounter a so-called black-box function in an algorithm. It&amp;rsquo;s called a black box since we don&amp;rsquo;t how it calculate the output from the input, but we do know the output it returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deutsch Algorithm (Part 2): Deutsch-Jozsa problem - The first exponential speedup</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-2-deutsch-jozsa-problem-the-first-exponential-speedup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:53:35 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-2-deutsch-jozsa-problem-the-first-exponential-speedup/</guid>
      <description>Here we&amp;rsquo;re gonna see the most impressive quantum algorithm in terms of query complexity. The algorithm is an generalization of the original Deutsch algorithm we discussed in the last post. But I want to say that this algorithm may not be as extraordinary as you may think of it. It was created to solve a kind of problem that has zero practical meaning for the purpose of demonstrating how strong quantum computing can reach compared to classical computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deutsch Algorithm (Part 1): Kicking the phase back</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-1-kicking-the-phase-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:57:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/05/deutsch-algorithm-part-1-kicking-the-phase-back/</guid>
      <description>I have said something like quantum computing can overpower classical computing several times before. In this series, I&amp;rsquo;m going to showing you a problem with a quantum algorithm that is exponentially faster in terms of complexity than any classical solution. In this text, we&amp;rsquo;re going to explore an essential technique and apply it to solve the simplest version of Deutsch problem.
 Phase kick-back One concept you may encouter numerous times in a Linear Algebra class is eigenvalues and eigenvectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Teleportation (Part 2): The Art of transporting the Unknown</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-2-the-art-of-transporting-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 15:26:47 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-2-the-art-of-transporting-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Suppose Trong has just created a wonderful qubit in his lab. He knows his qubit look like $|\psi\rangle = \alpha |0\rangle + \beta |1\rangle$ but doesn&amp;rsquo;t know $\alpha$ and $\beta$. Now he wants to transport this qubit to his crush, but they don&amp;rsquo;t have a quantum channel that can help transport quantum information. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s a very bad idea for Trong to try to figure out $\alpha$ and $\beta$ through measurement because if he does so, he&amp;rsquo;ll destroy his qubit but only learn extremely little information about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Teleportation (Part 3): Implementation</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-3-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 15:26:47 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-3-implementation/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s implement and verify the teleporation protocol following the procedure we discussed throughout previous parts.
First we need to create an arbitrary quantum state. Trong has been curious about the combined effect of rotation gates about the x, y, and z axes. So, he decides to apply three distinct rotation gates, each as a rotation of 60 degrees around one coordinate axis acting on a qubit currently in the Hadamard state $|-\rangle$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Teleportation (Part 1): Preliminaries</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-1-preliminaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 15:26:46 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/quantum-teleportation-part-1-preliminaries/</guid>
      <description>Here we start exploring a core of Quantum Computing: Quantum Algorithms. Before we dive into the dark and deep pool of such algorithms, it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to get familiar with a fundamental constraint to Quantum Computing. In contrast, I&amp;rsquo;ll also introduce you how powerful qubits get in solving problems through a basic protocol: Quantum Teleportation, the &amp;ldquo;Hello, world!&amp;rdquo; of Quantum Programming.
 No-cloning theorem In terms of computer architechture, it&amp;rsquo;s convenient to copy the state of a bit in order to create a new qubit exactly the same.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>