<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantum Information on My Entangled: Blogging on Quantum Information, Quantum Algorithms and Quantum Computing</title>
    <link>https://myentangled.com/en/categories/quantum-information/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quantum Information on My Entangled: Blogging on Quantum Information, Quantum Algorithms and Quantum Computing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 22:52:02 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://myentangled.com/en/categories/quantum-information/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Randomized Benchmarking (Part 2): Protocols for standard and interleaved versions &#43; Experiment with a realistic quantum device</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/08/randomized-benchmarking-part-2-protocols-for-standard-and-interleaved-versions-experiment-with-a-realistic-quantum-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 22:52:02 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/08/randomized-benchmarking-part-2-protocols-for-standard-and-interleaved-versions-experiment-with-a-realistic-quantum-device/</guid>
      <description>Knowing the underpinnings of randomized benchmarking addressed in the last part, we first begin with the standard protocol. Standard RB is used to assess the error rate over gates of Clifford group with an assumption that these gates have the same error rate. After that, another improvement of the technique will be introduced, namely Interleaved Randomized Benchmarking. The upgraded version was proposed not to investigate the Clifford group as a whole, but restricted to one single kind of Clifford gate of our choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randomized Benchmarking (Part 1): A fast, robust, and scalable assessment of Clifford gates</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/randomized-benchmarking-part-1-a-fast-robust-and-scalable-assessment-of-clifford-gates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 22:50:45 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/randomized-benchmarking-part-1-a-fast-robust-and-scalable-assessment-of-clifford-gates/</guid>
      <description>As you can see in the cover figure, quantum computing is just at the onset of its journey. There are tons of work to do before we can move to the next stage of quantum computing, quantum supremacy. Two pivotal constraints to the realization of any useful quantum processor are decoherence and the high error rate of quantum operators, or quantum gates experimentally. It&amp;rsquo;s been suggested that the probability of error per unitary gate should be less than $10^{-2}$ (better $10^{-4}$) for the outcome to be reliable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error rate vs Fidelity (Part 1): Unveil the mathematics behind quantum error rate</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/error-rate-vs-fidelity-part-1-unveil-the-mathematics-behind-quantum-error-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 16:39:35 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/error-rate-vs-fidelity-part-1-unveil-the-mathematics-behind-quantum-error-rate/</guid>
      <description>In the article of Bernsterin-Vazirani implementation, I&amp;rsquo;ve addressed one of the most crucial challenges of quantum computing. The field is yet to flourish because quantum gates aren&amp;rsquo;t constructed to be good enough. One major difference of quantum gates versus classical counterparts is that quantum gates have to be reversible, which means we&amp;rsquo;re able to retrieve a prior state of a qubit without loss of information. Scientists are now on their way to establish a proper scheme for building decent quantum gates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed States and General Quantum Operations: A simple view on the framework of Quantum Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/mixed-states-and-general-quantum-operations-a-simple-view-on-the-framework-of-quantum-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 23:45:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/07/mixed-states-and-general-quantum-operations-a-simple-view-on-the-framework-of-quantum-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>In this text I&amp;rsquo;ll do some review on the definition of quantum state and quantum measurement, which was introduced here, and reasonably expand the notions into the most general instances of quantum bits.
Review Given a state $$|\psi\rangle = \sum_i \alpha_i |\varphi_i \rangle,$$ it&amp;rsquo;s possible to perform a Von Neumann measurement on the state&amp;rsquo;s space $\mathscr{H}$ with respect to the orthonormal basis $B = \{|\varphi_i \rangle\}$. The output would be a label $i$ with corresponding probability $|\alpha_i|^2$ and the system left in state $|\varphi_i\rangle$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A formal approach to Observables and Measurements</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/a-formal-approach-to-observables-and-measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 11:09:30 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/04/a-formal-approach-to-observables-and-measurements/</guid>
      <description>Throughout previous posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve delivered a way to understand what is a quantum measurement. That way of understanding is simple and may suit our normal intuition, but measurement is a non-trivial physical process and somewhat counter-intuitive for several reasons.
First, a measurement in general results in probabilistic outcomes. No matter how careful you prepare for the measurement procedure, it is inherent that possible outcomes of a measure is distributed according to a certain probability distribution determined by the state space of your quantum system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Operations: Unitary and Reversible Matrices</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-operations-unitary-and-reversible-matrices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 10:58:21 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-operations-unitary-and-reversible-matrices/</guid>
      <description>Source of image: Quantum Computer Explained - Limits of Human Technology  (Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell) 
In classical computation, there are four basic operations that act on information bits, namely Identity (no operation), Negation (NOT), Conjunction (AND), and Disjunction (OR). All other operations are secondary and built upon these four operations. That being said, with the primary and secondary operations, one is able to perform any calculation in classical fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Entanglement to cheat the Reality</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-entanglement-to-cheat-the-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 23:59:42 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-entanglement-to-cheat-the-reality/</guid>
      <description>Quantum entanglement Have you ever thought of a situation when the happening of an event in an isolated environment dictates the result of another event also in an isolated environment with no communication allowed? That sounds infeasible in our view of reality, except that these two separated events share a somewhat telepathic power. Yes, this telepathy really happens in the realm of quantum entanglement. The phenomenon can be simplified that the result of the first measurement reveals information about the result of the second measurement despite an absolute separation and no communication setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Measurement: Not just 0 and 1</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-measurement-not-just-0-and-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 10:58:21 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/quantum-measurement-not-just-0-and-1/</guid>
      <description>Quantum entanglement is, by definition, a phenomenon that the combined state of a set of qubits cannot be described as a product of the states of each qubit of that set, which also means the entangled state contains hidden information that one cannot reveal through examining separate qubits. In this text, I&amp;rsquo;m going to introduce and discuss several aspects of this spectacular phenomenon.
Measurement in different bases In previous posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned that a qubit can be in a superposition of its basis states $\left|0\right\rangle$ and $\left|1\right\rangle$ with corresponding complex amplitudes $a_0$ and $a_1$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qubits: The substitution of bits in quantum scenario</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/qubits-the-substitution-of-bits-in-quantum-scenario/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 16:39:36 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/qubits-the-substitution-of-bits-in-quantum-scenario/</guid>
      <description>Source of image: Quantum Computer Explained - Limits of Human Technology  (Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell) 
As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned in my previous post, qubits doesn&amp;rsquo;t suffer from the limitation of only being $0$ or $1$. Within this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about some background knowledge essential for ones who have just stepped into the field like me.
Single Qubit Dirac notation $\left | \cdot \right\rangle$ (pronounced as ket) is adopted to indicate qubit states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A half-alive-half-dead cat and the beginning of Quantum Information</title>
      <link>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/a-half-alive-half-dead-cat-and-the-beginning-of-quantum-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 19:47:20 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://myentangled.com/en/2019/03/a-half-alive-half-dead-cat-and-the-beginning-of-quantum-information/</guid>
      <description>You may have heard of quantum information promising many prospects in revolutionizing the future of computers? When I was a high-schooler years ago, I also got amazed by these statements repeated in pop science articles. But to what extent this statement is true? Before we come to a final conclusion, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look on historical milestones of the field.
The duration from the 1900s to 1930s was the golden age of quantum mechanics with many groundbreaking findings that established a concrete theoretical foundation for quantum information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>